Kaustuv Pokharel

STUDENT

🔀 kastuvpokharel@gmail.com	+1 (6)	647) 624-2171	♥ Toronto ON	I, Canada
in www.linkedin.com/in/kaustuv	okharel	www.beha	ınce.net/kaustu	vpokharel3

PROFILE

A highly motivated and ambitious sophomore software engineering student with a passion for system programming, embedded systems, and software development. Proficient in programming languages such as C/C++/Python. Currently expanding knowledge in QT to deepen expertise. Demonstrated ability to quickly learn and apply new technologies, work well under pressure, and effectively communicate with team members and stakeholders.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

QT/QML	Bash / Zsh	
C/C++	Blender 3D	
Python	Adobe After Effects	
SQL	Adobe Illustrator	
STM32/Embedded	Adobe Photoshop	
Git	Microsoft Office Suite	

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern

Bell Canada *May 2024 - Aug 2024* Upcoming 2024 Summer Internship.

President

Seneca Science & Technology Guild Mar 2023 - Present

- 130+ members
- Represent the college at hackathons and other technology competitions.
- Foster a culture of innovation and collaboration within the club.
- Build and maintain relationships with industry professionals and organizations.

https://clubs.ssfinc.ca/senecascitech/seneca-scitech/

3D Artist/Motion Graphics Artist

SunBi Holdings Pvt. Ltd. Jan 2021 - Aug 2022

- Create motion graphics animations, 3D renders, and lottie files for internet use.
- Handle lighting, shading, materials, textures, and various 3D simulations.
- Design vector and raster graphics.
- Communicate with client servicing and content teams to meet deadlines.
- Advise and implement changes where and when required (as per client's feedback).

https://www.behance.net/kaustuvpokharel3

Mentor / Advisor

Trinity Science and Technology Guild Jul 2020 - Jan 2022

- · Guilding and mentoring juniors with their projects
- Recruiting additional qualified robotics and technology enthusiasts from the college.

President

Trinity Students' Club Sep 2018 - Jun 2020

- Organizing all the major inter/intra college programs/events.
- Lead all other six college clubs.
- Representing college in all the major programs/events, bringing honors to the college.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Next-Generation Firewall (NGFW)

Developed for hackathon(from scratch)

- Build with C++/QT and Python
- · Real-time packet capture and analysis for network monitoring.
- Multithreaded packet capture for efficiency.
- Implemented socket communication with a remote server.
- · Integrated AI for intelligent packet analysis.

https://github.com/kastuv/FireWall_Version2/tree/firewall_server

Neural Network In C

Developed from scratch

- · Became familiar with AI fundamentals and matrices
- Basic understanding of neurons, synapses, and action potentials (Neuroscience)
- Developed an understanding of deep learning from a C programming perspective
- Understood how hidden weights, bias, and activation functions work
- · Built deep learning libraries in C

https://github.com/kastuv/neuralNetwork-in-C.git

ToDo-Desktop App with QT

Developed from scratch

- Deeper understanding of Classes in OT
- · Signals and slots core knowledge
- C++ algorithms and problem solving

https://github.com/kastuv/QT-Todo-desktopAPP.git

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Engineering: Software Engineering

Seneca Polytechnic Sep 2022 - Present

Relevant coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Software Design and Development, Programming Languages, and Computer Networks, Maths(calculus I & II, Linear algebra, discrete, statistics).

Computer Science

Trinity International College Jun 2018 - Jul 2020

Relevant coursework: Maths, Science and Computer.

COMPETITIONS & AWARDS

Bell (GeekFest) - Honorable Mention

https://clubs.ssfinc.ca/senecascitech/next-generation-firewall-/

Smart City Hackathon - Finalist

https://clubs.ssfinc.ca/senecascitech/seneca-smart-cities-hackathon-2023/

LANGUAGES

English	Nepali				
Hindi/Urdu	Bengali		0	0	0

STRENGTHS

- Strong proficiency in C/C++/python/SQL and a guick learner of new languages.
- Knowledge of the QT framework/Database Management and constantly expanding skills.
- Experienced with Linux, macOS, and Windows operating systems.
- Proficient in Bash/Zsh scripting language.
- Familiar with software development methodologies i.e development, deployment & testing.
- · Skilled in troubleshooting and debugging code.